Päärni, Risto Anton

Helsinki, Finland

Summary

My name is Risto Anton Päärni, M.Sc./B.Sc. engineer focusing on AWS project Lifetime Digital Workspace for Intelligent Industries (dws), an InvestEU approved, EBAN funded project at the moment.

I was chosen to participate in Smart Factory/ Industrial internet Cloud M.S. Program in Metropolia Applied Science 2022-2024, so I am looking for a company to work with and to deliver a Research & Development to customer projects. My Research areas are edge and cloud and its security, and building sustainable ESG Smart Factory solutions and applications and managing its fleet..

As a professional, I offer three hats to your team, namely agile Scrum Project Manager, Cloud Solutions Architect, and Cloud Developer (C++/C#, React, Node.JS, Python, Docker, GitHub Actions CICD).

As CEO of Lifetime Group my backlog of duties include solution sales, consultative sales approach, business development, funding, innovation and brand management, leading the team and projects, seeing over the operations of the company, HR, marketing, management accounting, nurturing client and partner relationships.

Risto Anton has public cloud experience for more than 10+ years. He is an experienced solutions architect with deep knowledge of customer business cases on apps services on AWS, Microsoft Azure, Google Cloud, IBM Cloud and with technologies like Kubernetes (k8s) hybrid cloud fleet and app services.



Risto Anton has expertise in data architecture design, cloud native based LITETIME GROUP services design and business model based service modeling, APIs, integration solutions and NoSQL / SQL databases. As security practitioner he is the Administrator of Lifetime Group 5 domains solving and managing their hands-on daily security and growth and CX issues.

Education

- Program älykäs teollisuus ko, YAMK, Metropolia, 2022-2024.
- Master of Industrial Management, DI, Technology Entrepreneurship, LUT, 2005-2007.
- Bachelor of Software Engineering, insinööri,1991.
 Metropolia, 1991. ICT Project Manager datanomi, Amiedu, 2017-2018.
- JYET, Leadership Program, BusinessCollege, 2019-2020.
- Matriculation examination, Myyrmäen lukio, 1983-1985.

Certifications

- AWS Architect Associate 2022. AWS Practitioner 2020.
- Foundation Certificate for Security, CISSP, 2022
- Level C Certified Project Management Professional, IPMA (International Project Management Association), 2022-2023.
- Microsoft Azure Academy, Microsoft Academy, Saranen. 2017-2018.
- Microsoft BizSpark 2015-2017. Building with Xamarin.

Risto Anton's Skills

Competence Area	Experience	Projects and solutions
Leading the consultative solution sales	15	in the year of 2022, Lifetime Group operates on
		the hybrid cloud environment delivering
		solutions and development projects on IBM
		Cloud, IBM Watson, Atlassian, Terraform Cloud,
		GitHub Actions, Tempo Planner, Tempo
		TimeSheets, Slack, Office 365 Business, G Suite
		Business, WordPress, Amazon Web Services,
		Microsoft Azure, Google Cloud, SAFe,
		kokonaisketterä, DevOps, GitHub, OpenShift,
		RedHat, k8, containers, Docker Professional, IBN
		Cloud Pak for Data.
Project, productivity and collaboration management	15	2022 my primary tasks:
		 scope definition, preparing business
		case and project plan, monitoring key
		milestones & approach, budget
		tracking, deviances management,
		project charter creation, status
		reporting, building tracking
Communication and teamwork	15	2022
Business development / innovation management	15	1. Which Region are you targeting?
, ,		Scandinavia Finland, Sweden, and Norway.
		2. Which Industry sector would you like to
		acquire?
		Smart Engineering, Digitally Moving, data
		transformation into Hybrid Cloud environment.
		transformation into Hybrid Cloud environment.
		3. Which Title/Job Designation would you like to
		reach?
		Those decision makers that are key to our sales
		targets, usually CEO/CIO/Architect/PM/POs/
Process development (eg. Lean)	10	2022 <u>Lifetime Group</u> builds value with
		continuous delivery/ solutions for the hybrid
		cloud. We are your Copilots on AWS, IBM Cloud,
		Google Cloud, Microsoft Azure, Terraform Cloud
		and with GitOps Business Development. We
		digitally copilot, move and transform your
		business to the next level.
Agile organization / SAFe / kokonaisketterä.fi	10	2022
Design thinking and Service Design	5	2022

Administer and Manage	30	Risto Anton is the Owner of Lifetime Group, CEO	
Continuous Delivery Software development	(years)	Your Go-To Copilots of Innovations and Solutions made of Hybrid Cloud/AI/ML/GitOps/Data-Driven/Automation/ Containers primary tasks:	
C Application Development with traditional C / C++ languages // using Microsoft Visual Studio 2022 64-bit // with CMake 3.23.2 // and GCC 7.3.0 // on Windows 11.0.0 // with Visual Studio Code 1.69.0	15		
Technical architecture or solution architecture design	10	2022	
.NET 6 Multi-platform App development UI with a cross-platform framework for creating mobile and desktop apps with C# 10 and XAML . with .NET MAUI developing native apps that run on Android, iOS, iPadOS, macOS, Tizen, Windows from a single shared codebase on GitHub. https://github.com/dotnet/maui	7	https://github.com/bitfighter/bitfighter Visual Studio 2022 Community Ubuntu WSL Docker	
Database design ORM architecture	7	Design a testing strategy Create detailed designs for a solution	
Build and version management on GitHub and Microsoft DevOps	7	2022	
Configuration management IaC Terraform cloud	7	2022	
Agile cicd for github actions -> Azure	7	2022	
API Design / gateway management	7	2022	
Cloud CI/CD Container fleet		Docker Desktop • CI/CD	
AWS	7	 Compute: WordPress laaS Bitnami with Virtual Machines Debian Linux managing machines. PaaS managed machines. Azure App Services, provisioning pre-built SaaS images Storage, Messaging, Data, Networking Serverless with Azure Functions and Azure Logic Apps Containers Docker / k8s Registry Production Kubernetes Services Azure Pipelines CI/CD 	
Microsoft Azure Developer	7	 Compute: Azure laaS with Virtual Machines Linux/Windows Docker managing machines PaaS managed machines. Running on Azure App Service, provisioning pre-built SaaS images and websites (web app architecture / API app) Storage, Messaging, Data, Networking Serverless with Azure Functions and Azure Logic Apps Container Docker images on k8s Azure Kubernetes Service Azure Pipelines CI/CD 	
Google Cloud	7	2022	
Test automation Snyk Developer Security GitHub Copilot	3	2022	
Telephone State Copies Security States Copies	7	2022	

4(10)

Performance testing	5	2022
Security testing Cybersecurity	5	2022
IT Infra	+	
IT Operations management Prometheus	7	2022
Data Science	5	2022
Ict security, continuous delivery Terraform	15	2022
Databases DynamoDB, Aurora, MariaDb	15	2022
Technical Skills	15	2022
HTML / CSS / XAML	15	2022
TypeScript	7	2022
JavaScript	15	
Angular.js / other .js framework	7	2022
<u> </u>	7	2022
Node.js Google Flutter		2022
C, C++, C#	7	2022
Golang	1	2022
.NET SDK	7	2022
AWS Toolkit, AWS CDK / CloudFormation / YAML / JSON	7	2022
Google Workspace Admin / GCE	10	2022
Python scripting / Jyputer	7	2022
React hooks	10	2022
Modeling / Business Model Development	15	2022
Product platforms		
Apache Spark 3.x / many	2	2022
IBM products Watson (Business Partner)	2	2022
IBM Cloud Paks	4	2022
Amazon Web Services (Consulting Partner)	4	2022
IBM DB2	2	2022
Postgres	2	2022
MySQL	10	2022
MS SQL Server	4	2022
MS Sharepoint Server	10	2022
MS Exchange Server / Office 365 Admin	7	2022
Ms Azure Architect	7	2022
MS DevOps	4	2022
MS Hyper V	15	2022
VMWare Tanzu, Bitnami	2	2022
Version management tools		2022
Git/ GitHub	7	2022
GitLab Community edition	5	2022
Atlassian JIRA	5	2022
Atlassian Confluence	5	
	3	2022
Mobile platforms Apple iOS	10	2022
		2022
Google Android	15	2022
OS platforms	+	
Apple OS X	6	2022
Linux Server / AMIs	15	2022
Windows Server / AMIs	15	2022
Testing tools	120	
DevSecOps DevSecOps	4	2022
Microsoft DevOps	5	2022
Sonarqube	0,2	LULL
JMeter	0,2	
	~, <u>~</u>	

5(10)

	1	I
Jenkins	0,2	2020
Software products		
SAP	6	2022
MSOffice 365 Power Apps	6	2022
Container technologies		
Docker	6	2022
Kubernetes Management Platforms: Tanzu, Rancher	4	2022
API platforms		
Azure API gateway	6	2022
AWS API gateway	6	2022
IBM API gateway	6	2022
Google API gateway	6	2022
Cloud services		
Terraform cloud	4	2022
MS Azure Solutions Architect	6	2022
MS Office 365 Admin	7	2022
Google Workspace Admin	15	2022
Amazon Web Services (AWS) Architect Associate	6	2022
Business Sector Knowledge	Experience in	Last Used in Project / Program
	years	
Insurance		
Finance	4	2022
Retail	12	
Healthcare	4	
Government	6	
Telecom	4	
Media	12	
Energy	4	
Building Construction		
Process Knowledge		
Finance	10+ years of	
· ····airioc	company	
	finance	
	process	
	experience	
Human Resources	10+ years of	
	consulting	
	team lead	
	experience	
IT Security and Administration	15+ years of IT	
	Administration	
	process	
	experience	
Software Engineering	15+ years of	
	experience	
Sales	10+ years of	
	sales process	
	experience	
	CRM,	
	Salesforce	<u> </u>
Marketing	10+ years of	
	marketing	
	process	
	experience	
Teaming	Google	
Teamwork	15+ Team	
	leader and	
	member in various	

Updated July 12th, 2022

businesses and	
industries	

Project experienceLifetime Digital Workspace for Intelligent Industries is an award winning project approved by the European Commission found here.

Project name: Lifetime Digital Workspace for Intelligent Industries Customer: Lifetime Group Certified Partners Consortium Time involved: 05/2018 - present	Description of project: What is the goal of the project Montreux (version 4)? What has been achieved so far? What is the desired outcome? Platform: AWS, Microsoft Azure AD, Linux AMIs Backend Services: DynamoDB, S3 datalake, see specs A. Frontend Services: Android, iOS, Metaverse AWS Services: See Appendix A. Own role(s): Project Manager, Cloud Solutions Architect, Developer Responsibilities: solution architecture for development, testing, production.	
	 database design, data lakehouse design UI design, mobile application, VR/AR design and implementation of DevOps and its Security 	
Project name: CIMS Customer: EBAN Time involved: 08/2015 -	 continuous integration and deployment Description of project: CIMS Platform: Microsoft Azure Software: HTML5, C# MS SQL Server, IIS Own role: Project Manager Responsibilities: managing project team of 5 specialists requirements specifications test planning, testing 	

Career history

Career history		
Lifetime Consulting 04/2018 - present	Job Title: Agile Project Manager Main responsibilities:	
	 Project Planning, Project Costs, Project Resourcing. 	
	Project Portfolio	
	Sprint Audit	
	with agile, kanban, GitHub Actions, JIRA	
	backlog owner	
	Budgeting, Reporting	
Lifetime Studios 04/2018 – present	Job Title: Cloud Developer Main responsibilities:	
	 Writing error-free code, Sprints work 	
	design and implementation of client solutions	
	administering all testing and environments blue/green	
	 testing DevSecOps tooling the client solution/ software 	
Lifetime Studios	Job Title: Cloud Architect	

	Main responsibilities
	 Main responsibilities: Writing error-free IaC code for Solutions Security of AWS Services Architectural design and implementation of client solutions administration of all testing and environments blue/green Strategy and Roadmap of DevSecOps, AMIs, Subscriptions tooling the client solution/ software. AWS Control Tower Management for Accounts Account Manager for client accounts. Containerization Team Leader for Projects.
Lifetime Oy 04/2018 -	Job Title: CEO Main responsibilities:

Language skills Finnish

Native speaker

Fluent in project work and remote environments Good Tjänstemans Språkprov

English Swedish

Basics German C#, Go, Node.JS, python, Fluent

GitOps

Smart Factory YAMK in Metropolia

Year	Course	Grade	Training provider
2022	Älykkäät teolliset ratkaisut	4 out of 5	Metropolia YAMK tutkinto
2022	Tutkimusmenetelmät ja valmiudet	4 out of 5	Metropolia YAMK
09/2022	Projektien johtaminen		Metropolia YAMK
10/2022	Sovellettu seminaari I	Reunalaskennan valmiudet ja menetelmät	Metropolia YAMK
10/2022-04/202 3	Sovellettu seminaari II	Kyberturvallisuuden valmiudet ja menetelmät	Metropolia YAMK
04/2023-12/23	Insinöörityö		Metropolia YAMK
2022	CISSP Certified Information Security Professional	8 ECTS	Metropolia YAMK
2022	AWS Architect Certification		Amazon Web Services
2022	Certified Project Manager		IPMA

8(10)

My AI Voice Interview (Answers updated)

What are you looking for in your next job?

As a Data Architect I want to analyze data sources and analyze data to find great solutions to the customer issues raised that they are facing in their business. To show customers data in appealing form is important, whether we use Tableau, Office 365, or other client tools.

As a Cloud Architect the building of new services for customer needs is important. Securing business continuity Identity Access Management, Monitoring, Containerization, SaaSes. Then there is security, Disaster Recovery Planning (DR), for example Business Continuity and Disaster Recovery with Amazon S3.

As Cloud Developer Building solid DevOps pipelines and teams associated with the right tooling and effective builds that follow secure policies like Snyk tooling, Git, Among others. IaC Scripts. I may lead a team or be a team member.

Tell me about a time you had to deliver on multiple competing priorities. What did you do, and what were the results?

When there are multiple competing priorities, first, me and my team must prioritize and sort out which top three solutions and answers we need to solve urgently for the client.

and then I want to make a critical road map for those following priorities for the company to prioritize project portfolio and to meet the goals that our customer has set for us.

You're putting together a presentation for a client using several data visualizations. What steps would you take in your final review of the presentation to make sure the information is clearly communicated?

In the presentation my team would state the problem first, then we would state the solution if available. Third, we would pinpoint the steps needed from the customer and from our side to reach a Go/No Go decision to deliver the solution to the customer problem.

10(10)

Updated July 12th, 2022

How can a subquery help aggregate data?

Subqueries are not generally allowed in aggregate functions. Instead, move the aggregate inside the subquery in SQL.

When do you try to push through and solve a problem on your own, and when do you involve others on your team?

I evaluate our team members. under capabilities along with my own capabilities the see which combination gives the best answer to solving the problem.